Contact





faisalmahir1221@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/in/mahirfaisal/

Twitter.com/MahirFaisal1221 faisalmahir.wordpress.com

Skills

Leadership & Teamwork

Customer Relationship Management

Written and Verbal Communication

Problem-solving & Design-thinking

Planning & Scheduling

Analytical and Critical Reasoning

Recruiting and Training

Research Analyzing

Software Skills

MS Office Package (Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Access, Teams), Google Workspace Suites, Zenefits (HRIS), Trello (Task Management), KoBoToolbox (Data Collection), Designing (Canva, PowerPoint), Social Media (Content Moderation)

Publication

THE HIDDEN COSTS OF MIGRATION:
EVALUATING THE BANGLADESH –
MALAYSIA CORRIDOR

by Winrock International & USAID Asia CTIP



MD MAHIR FAISAL

Dynamic Manager with consistent efforts to learn beyond the scope of conventions. My exposure to business and development for around 2 years led me to build my capacity in managerial roles and made me a highly organized and smart-working individual. Passionate to pursue a challenging career in sales, where I can bring my business knowledge and skills. I love traveling, exploring, and networking with people.

Work History

Nov 2021 -Current

Manager- Business Development & HR

SELL BEE, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Identifying needs for business development, strategic planning for sales, monitoring customer experiences, and growth strategies.
- Ensuring the responsibilities of achieving all the KPIs including the sales target.
- Managing customer services with a target of building relationships.
- Managing Recruitment, Org. Development, Training, Employer branding, KPI, etc.

Nov 2020 – Nov 2021

Research Associate (PR and Field Research Coordination)

Winrock International, and USAID Asia CTIP (Concealed Perils of Migration)

Bangladesh & Malaysia

Project: The Hidden Costs of Migration: the Bangladesh-Malaysia Corridor funded by USAID Asia CTIP and Implemented by Winrock International.

- Managed Data collection team; Associated recruitment, Training, and Performance Management;
- Coordinated Field Research Team.
- Associated researches; Data collection, validity & consistency checks.
- Liaised with external and internal parties; proposal and report writing.

Aug 2020 – Nov 2020

Management Intern

Office of Deputy Rector (Internationalization): Office of Promotion and Marketing (OPM), **International Islamic University Malaysia**, Malaysia

- Associated the office of Deputy Rector & OPM with Administrative responsibilities.
- Worked with Digital Marketing, & Record Management systems.
- Associated the head of Marketing with strategies and campaign designs.

April 2020 – Aug 2021

Deputy Lead, Grassroots Network (Part-time)

Youth Policy Forum, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Lead grassroots policy network (Planning, Implementation, Monitoring & Evaluation); Developed proposals and reports for multiple events & partnerships.
- Associated the core team (with Policy research, Social media outreach, Transcribing FDI webinars, and National Budget Analysis (FY 20-21)).
- Recruited & Trained Envoys, Managed database & updated it promptly with KPI.
- Conducted FGDs with grassroots to transpose their needs into policy as a part of Policy Research; Worked with minority rights advocacy campaign in Sunamganj.
- Coordinated event with UNDP and GP (GET FUTURE READY: Need For Skills).

Oct 2018 -June 2019

Executive Sales Officer (Part-Time)

Vaquero Foods Sdn. Bhd., Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Liaised with customers and sales team regarding Food menus, pricing, and offers.
- Additionally, managed an outlet for 2 months; Managed Orders and distribution

Leadership Experience

Organizing Volunteer(Coordination)

Blockchain Olympiad Bangladesh,
 2021 & International Blockchain
 Olympiad, 2021 - 1 year

Vice President(HR)- Bangladeshi Students' Organization Malaysia (BSOM)- 3 years

Information Secretary- Economics and Management Science Society, IIUM - 3 years

Fellow Volunteer- Shopnaloron Bangladesh (Local Org.) - 2 years

Language

Bengali - Native

English - Professional

Interests and Hobbies

Traveling, Social Works, Blog Writing, Mentoring, Reading, Photography, Cooking

Education

2015-09 - 2020-11

Bachelor of Business Administration (Hons.)

International Islamic University Malaysia, Malaysia (IIUM)

Concentrated in Human Resource Management.

2012-07 - 2014-08

Higher Secondary Certificate: Business Studies

Monipur High School and College - Dhaka, Bangladesh

Training & Certifications

	(Humanitarian Leadership Academy, Save The Children)
2021	Training and Development for Managers

2021 Introduction to Proposal and Report Writing

(Save The Children)

2020 JDR3 Scholars Program training Policy Influence in Social Science

Research.

(USAID and Winrock International)

2020 Business Analysis Foundation

(International Institute of Business Analysis)

2020 Administrative Human Resources

(HR Certification Institute-HRCI)

2020 Creating a Positive and Healthy Work Environment

(Society for HRM.)

2019 Executive Leadership

(Project Management Inst.)

2019 Strategic Thinking

(Project Management Inst.)

References

Sadman Masood

(Concealed Perils of Migration, Winrock

International)
Marketing Manager
Wagely

Phone: +8801323877976

Email: sadmanmasood@gmail.com

Tahmina Sharmin

(International Blockchain Olympiad

Bangladesh 2021)

Head of Quality Assurance, Technohaven Company Ltd. Phone: +8801685820108

Email: sharmin@technohaven.com